Guide to the Mitchell-Tiffany Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1850-1910; Series VI; 9.5 linear feet (11 boxes)
  - Album 6: Album, tooled leather binding, brown (Box 37, Folder 30)
    Page 1: "Sunflower Lodge," New London Page 2: Mrs. C. L. Tiffany, New York Page 3: Mary ("May") Woodbridge Goddard (Mrs. L. C. Tiffany) Page 4: L. to r. Susan, Rebecca, Hesse, Donald, Jr., children of Donald Grant Mitchell Page 5: Donald Grant Mitchell ("Ik Marvel") Page 6: Charles Lewis Tiffany with granddaughter Charly Tiffany Mitchell (b.1877) Page 7: Annie Olivia Tiffany Mitchell and daughter Alfreda (b. 1874); doll; Charly T. Mitchell (?); Burnett Young Tiffany Page 8: (German photo); unidentified; Julia Goddard Piatt (?); Donald O. Mitchell, Jr. (?) and dog Page 9: ? (Paris); ? (Maderia); Annie O. Tiffany (New York) about 1870; Alfred Mitchell (tin-type) about 1870 Page 10: Alfred Mitchell, Captain in uniform, about 1863; Annie O. Tiffany (Norwich) about 1870; Alfreda Mitchell, about 1879; Charly T. Mitchell, about 1879 Page 11: "Charly" (age 4 (?); Charly Tiffany Mitchell [?] (age 3 (?); Charly Tiffany Mitchell and Alfreda Mitchell (ages 2 & 4); Charly Tiffany Mitchell [?] (age 2 (?) New York Page 12: Painting by Carlo Dolce, Dresden; Dutch girl; ? (Poughkeepsie); Ryerson baby, Chicago. "For Uncle Lon with love from Minnie" Page 13: Charly T. Mitchell, Kensington, London, about 1892 Page 14: Unidentified 2 year old, Worcester Page 15: Unidentified boy and girl, Boston Page 16: Young girl with baby, probably Maymay & Charles Tiffany Page 17: Girl with dolls, Worcester, Massachusetts Page 18: Two young ladies with man, Naples Page 19: Baby in christening dress, Norwich Page 20: Alfred Mitchell, New York about 1875? Page 21: Young woman Page 22: Baby, Norwich Page 23: Joseph & Mary Ryerson, Chicago 1883? (age 4 & 2) Page 24: Painting of Dutch scene Page 25: Girl, Paris; "Mary F. Ogden, Aug. 1, 1890," New York; Woman, New London; Mary Ogden?, Breshan Page 26: 2 children swimming, New London; Alfred Mitchell on horse, 3 children, ships, dogs, New London; Mother & child, Hanover Page 27: Small boy, Providence; Baby, New York; Walter Mitchell?, age 3?, New Haven; Donald Mitchell, age 5 years, Edward Larned, age 3, 1889; Ryersons, Chicago Page 28: Young girls with man in garden; Young girls with woman in garden; Alfreda & Charly Mitchell with parents in New York about 1889; Unidentified boy Page 29: Hesse & Harriet Mitchell, 1893; Alfreda Flacksbart, April 1875,Hanover; Fishwives, Lisbon; Little girl, Hanover "November 96" Page 30: Unidentified woman; Fatme George V (?) Eton; Unidentified woman, New York; Music teacher. "Freda Mitchell zur erinerung an den Musiken"(?) Juni 1887, Hanover Page 31: Alfred Mitchell with wife & daughters about 1889 Page 32: Baby "Eleanor" Slater? "1889", Norwich Page 33: Small child, (Bloomingdale Bros. photo) Page 34: Ryerson child?, Oakland, California Page 35: Ryerson boy?, Los Angeles Page 36: Young woman. Anna Nevins?
  - Album 7: "Portraits (Miscellaneous) " (Box 38, Folder 31)
    Page 1: F. L. Peck; Captain Keeney; Robert Ripley; Alice Peck; Judge Morse, Ella Baker; H. D. Goddard; Kanuk Abbot Page 2: Schoolmate of Annie O. Mitchell; Helen Severance; Mrs. A. H. Almy; Dora Smith; Apthorp; Lizzie Townsend Page 3: Henry Dyer's son; Lucretia (Christophers) Mumford 1750-1825; Mrs. J. B. Young; John Almy; Nicholas Beach Page 4: Oliver Tweedy; Nicholas Beach; Mary Hoffman; Lizzie Townsend; Charlotte (Morse) Dunham; John Almy Page 5: Robert & Helen Ripley; Nellie Tyler (Philadelphia); Newton Perkins; Mrs. Hutchin's daughter Mrs. Geo. Tyler; Mr. & Mrs. Stockwell Page 6: Fred Terry; Fred Terry; Judge Green; Rose Goddard; Abby Backus Page 7: Mrs. B. R. Almy; Mrs. Stockwell; Mary Tyler (Philadelphia); H. P. Goddard; Nicholas Beach; John Welch (Madeira) Page 8: Jas. S. Norton; Mrs. Stockwell; Henry Dyer; Henry A. Ferguson Page 9: Mrs. C. A. Williams (Honolulu); C. A. Williams; Mary Bond; Sue Bishop; Mrs. Calvin Goddard Page 10: R. Swain Gifford; H. P. Goddard; Lily Perkins; Sister of Mrs. Donn Piatt (Cincinnati); Mrs. B. R. Sling; French Governess "Louise" Page 11: Molly Davenport; Mary Hoffman; Stansbury Hager; William Williams; Mary Williams (as teenagers); Apthorp Page 12: Mr. & Mrs. Stockwell; Lesseps & children (in carriage) Page 13: W. H. Tiffany ("My Uncle Henry, AOM"); A. B. Stockwell; Josie Perry; Henry Gray Page 14: Dr. & Mrs. Hosrack (?); Elias Perkins; H.H. Butterworth Page 15: Mrs. Spalding Page 16: Spalding; Ryerson; Walter M; Ryersons Page 17: "Starting from Nice 1867. LBY. Louis C. Tiffany, Annie O. Mitchell in coach (LCT in top hat) Page 18: Son of Morrill of Kansas; Son of Henry Dyer; Mrs. C.H. Judd; Phillip Rice Page 19: Mrs. Judd; May (Lockwood) Geli-Didof; Emily Rice; C.R. Bishop (Honolulu) Page 20: Princess of Wales; Prince Albert Edward (with parents); Lieutenant Joseph Bromley, AQM 13th Connecticut Volunteers; W.H. Rice (Kanai, Hawaii); Mrs. Rice Page 21: Captain Hubbard, A.A. [?] to General Weitgzel. Killed Port Hudson; May 27, 1863; Brigadier General Godfrey Weitzel; Lieutenant W-otnowski, A.D.C. to General Weitzel. Killed May 27, 1863; Colonel Holcomb, killed June 14, 1863, Port Hudson; Major Lieutenant C.C. Augur; Colonel E.L. Molineux, 159th Regiment, New York Volunteers Page 22: HRH Princess Kaiulani (age 18); Mary Anderson; Girton girl-- married a Parsee; Nellie McClure (Mrs. Sargent) Page 23: W.H. Hall & family (5 children). Honolulu Page 24: Mrs. Henry Villard & daughter Page 25: Anna Rice; Halfbreed Hawaiian; Rebecca & Harry (Edgewood) Page 26: W. H. Rice (Kanai, Hawaii); Lydia Almy (baby); Bond family: Hattie, Will (father), mother, Harry Page 27: Perry grandson (Osborn); Bertha Sherlock, Hattie Bond, Sue, Rebecca Riggs; Miss Ellen Wendt; Eleanor Slater 1889 (baby); Adelia Page 28: Mrs. Judge Morse ("My father's sister, Annie O. Mitchell") Page 29: Sons of Henry Villard; Miss Fanny Richter (2) (governess) Page 30: Anna Nevins Page 31: Judge (Walter) Mitchell; Stanley Trott; Henry Huntington DGM's Alfred's friend, Paris Page 32: Mrs. Dr. N. S. Perkins; Stanley G. Trott; Mrs. J. C. G. Piatt; Mrs. L. H. Goddard Page 33: Mrs. Joseph Sargent; Eleanor Slater; Mrs. D. G. Mitchell; Mrs. A. H. Almy; Mrs. Severence(Hilo, Hawaii) Page 34: Mrs. J. B. Young ("Auntie"); Mrs. A. H. Almy; Eleanor Slater (baby, on donkey); Mrs. J. B. Young Page 35: Mrs. W. A. Slater (age 25?) Page 36: Mitchell girls Edgewood (6); Eleanor & Willie Slater; Louise cTiffany & Nell Peck Page 37: W. A. Slater (age 35?) and Willie (age 6 mos.) Page 38: Count Benoit Tyskiewitcz (hunter) Page 39: Countess Tyskiewitcz Page 40: Children of Count & Countess Tyskiewitcz Page 41: B. Y. Tiffany (age 25?)
  - Album 8: Album, brown grained leather binding. Stamped A.M." (Box 38, Folder 32)
    Page 1: Alfred Mitchell (2 pictures), about 1890 Page 2: E. Alfreda and Charly Mitchell with mother, 1882?; Alfreda and Charly Mitchell Page 3: Annie O. Tiffany Mitchell about 1885; Alfred Mitchell about 1885 Page 4-5: Harriet Young; Charles L. Tiffany Page 6: Louis C. Tiffany, 1871; Louise H. Tiffany, 1871 Page 7: Annie O. Tiffany, 1871; Burnett Y. Tiffany, 1871 Page 8: Louise Harriet Tiffany, 1876? (2 pictures) Page 9: Louise H. Tiffany & Harriet Young Tiffany, 1880?; Mary Woodbridge (Mrs. Levi Hart) Goddard [?] Page 10: "Maymay" Tiffany, with Hilda & Charles L. Tiffany II, 1881?; Young woman, London Page 11: Eleanor Slater; Wm. A. Slater & Willie (baby) Page 12: Harriet Young (Mrs. Chas. L.) Tiffany; 2 babies in hammock with mothers? Page 13: Babies(2 pictures) Page 14: BLANK Page 15: 2 children; 4 children, Worcester "Received March 1887 at Florence" Page 16: Elizabeth and Rebecca Mitchell; Rebecca Mitchell (Mrs. Walter Hart) Page 17: Louis Mitchell (died 1881) (2 pictures) Page 18: Father & small daughter, New York; Girl, New York, "1888" Page 19: German royalty?, Berlin (2 pictures) Page 20: Walter Mitchell?; Unidentified Page 21: Unidentified; Hilda Tiffany? Page 22: Vatican boy, Florence, Italy; Marie, Susie and Lillie Metcalf, Florence, Italy, 1887 Page 23: Two small boys, Florence, Italy; "à Mme Mitchell, un souvenir de sincère affection de Billa, Stella et Elise Caminarano, Florence 28 avril 1887…" avec 1'espérance de rejoindre mes chères élèves en Amerique…" Page 24: 2 unidentified Page 25: Woman, Mary Ironsides (Hammond)? Page 26: Reproduction of 18th century man's portrait: Haydn Page 27: Woman, Chicago; 2 little girls in nursery "Alfreda & Berna in ihrer Kinderstube Weichuachten 1898." Page 28: Dresden gallery pictures (2) Page 29: Josef Hoffman at the piano, age about 7 Page 30: Metcalf children, Florence, Italy Page 31: Six children (4 are in #15, Worcester) Page 32: "My dear Mrs. Mitchell from the boy she loves and who loves her.; Charles Sheldon Judd. Taken Jan/99, Honolulu Page 33: "Charles Lewis Tiffany 2d. Compliments of Jack and Tonzer."; 2 dogs. Utica; Couple with cats & dog Page 34: Young woman, Philadelphia Page 35: 2 fox terriers; Alfred Mitchell about 1875 Page 36: BLANK
  - Copy negatives made from photographs in the albums (Box 38, Folder 33)